Hello, let's stay important today, let's
clear the confusion about insurance.
What would you think about both Mediclaim policy and Health Insurance and let me
tell you that the purpose of both is that, so let's
start and know what is the
difference, they only cover your hospitalization
expenses, let's understand both of them one by one,
in cashless settlement, if you are
admitted to the hospital for any reason, then you do
not have to pay the bill for the treatment expenses, that is,
cashless settlement, how is this bill created, directly
between the hospital and the insurance company and in this the
settlement of bills is done under the PIE i.e. third
party administrator,
now while getting admitted to the hospital,
you have to submit your Mediclaim card to the hospital, in
which the
process of commenting on the bill after admission was completed easily in a custom manner,
now these are some things that you
need to keep in mind at the time of cashless treatment,
that is, the office, like you have
got this policy of mine, contains a list of all those hospitals
where you
can get treatment, so before getting admitted to any hospital for
treatment, you  Find out
whether the hospital
is included in your mediclaim network hospitals or not
and you can get treatment in the same hospital
which has an agreement with the insurance company,
but sometimes such a situation also arises
when the hospital you are admitted in is
not included in the list of mediclaim hospitals, so
what happens in such a situation, when can your hospital
reimburse you, that means first you
pay the hospital bill and then you will get that amount as
reimbursement and this
whole process may take some time, all
you have to do is to get the reimbursement done, you will have to
contact the third party administrator, that is TPA, and your
expenses will be deducted, now
these are some things that
need to be kept in mind regarding the mediclaim policy
and yes, my tip is that at
least 24 hours of
hospitalization is necessary to avail the benefits of the policy,
we will tell you some more similarities and differences, but
before that, know that Informatics has 300
comprehensive health plans which
cover your hospitalization expenses
Apart from this, by covering all these expenses per hospitalization,
opposite hospitalization and ambulance expenses, it
means a very
wide security scope. In this also, in case of an accident or
serious illness like critical
illness, if there is any impact on your income
and your earning capacity, then
your policy compensates for it. For
example, if someone is
diagnosed with a serious illness, then your
policy gives you a lump sum amount on detection of the disease
or if they have to undergo surgery, then
you get a large amount for that expense also. One of the features in this is
that preventive health checkup is also included in your health
insurance. If you have taken a critical helpline, it is
included in it.
What is the basic difference between these two, you health
insurance policy and mediclaim policy. First of all, in
mediclaim policy, we
told you that 24-hour hospitalization is
necessary, there is no connection with these cities,
you do not need to be admitted in the hospital for 24 hours because even if your
treatment is day-to-day, that is, it is famous in the country, then
also you can take the benefit of your health insurance, you
can claim it.
Secondly, you  Mediclaim policy has multiple sums
and you can claim multiple sums till the end. For example, if
you have a policy of Rs 5 lakh and have
paid only Rs 2 lakh, then
you can claim the remaining Rs 3 lakh multiple times during the policy period.
Whereas, if you have a critical
illness plan or minor disability coverage, then this
amount is paid to you as a lump
sum i.e. one sum. Suppose,
after the illness is detected, the
medical policy will take care of it.
You can add your husband or wife along with yourself, you can add
your dependent children,
you can also add your dependent parents.
In some conditions, you
can also add these people. The similarity between the two is
that
you can avail the benefit of Section 8D of Income Tax in both.
Now the question is what should you take?
Understand this. If you are employed, then it is
possible that you will have a Mediclaim policy from your office,
but it will cover only your
hospitalization expenses.
This Mediclaim policy will
not be applicable to you as long as you are employed in that company.  As for my pimples, it is not even about that, that is why
we always talk about a separate comprehensive
health policy which you should have in
which you should
also add a critical illness plan,
so now why is it necessary to have a
separate health insurance, what are the benefits of taking it separately, what are its
nuances, we will talk about this in detail in one of our
next videos, but for how much
health insurance is necessary, your
city, your age and your lifestyle, your
ability to cover the expenses of any medical emergency,
you must have that much health insurance,
here always keep in mind that
before taking any policy, we should compare it and you can
easily get a lower price online, like
add the premium amount of the policy,
you can comment on how much is the green settlement rate behind it, you
can easily buy the policy online or keep the
insurance tax, do
not think that insurance is just a means of saving tax, that it is
your companion in difficult times, take care of yourself,
Namaste.